she is she is here today and i know im
sure i know im Dennis hello i'm derek
on visual
I'm bringing some explanations of what
the heck US envoys refugee heck of them
that happened two weeks ago here in we
will talk about some of the talks that
happened into europe cool 2015 that
happened just a few days ago at sites
work for example one talk about the
sonic power which is music library for
Westbury parents written in Ruby and
gaming library contact also and another
talk that borrows about how to cut any
polygon by just one cut if you have one
piece of paper and sisters South Beach
strange but you will get the details
later and we talked about the human
resource machine it's a game yes its
legs correctional but I'll be joining in
a conversation with horse about our
incredible road trip to Maker Faire Roma
associations of teaching making a key we
make him a key ok sure you wish
individual cheese and I was already
hearing you were covered in the Austrian
value that's that's correct we have been
on digital Living Translation germany
was ticket I'll leave that was quite
interesting as well because suddenly
people arriving from austin radio which
were not expecting to come up to show up
but more about the refugees it happened
two weeks ago was located at two of the
coworking spaces from the second 1 stock
friendly enough or kind enough to offer
us the rooms for the programming session
and absolutely absolutely organized by
enthusiasts you can still find
everything online even on an English
page if I remember correctly this URL
for this is doctor and starting
informations and on Friday seven
projects
introduced which had either already been
started by enthusiasts are we're just in
the face of getting started and founded
groups to started this project and in
the beginning I was very interested to
join the project about opening day time
which is mourners it is public in the
sense that you can get to it but it's
not in a very useful format for example
its statement
its yes it's an open beta thing and they
do which is hidden in PDS target was to
get it online in the sense that they can
either exes are exes it by machines if
it's exported to see fires or even
better in winter freeze you can easily
accessible excessive without any
programming knowledge and that was very
interested into that program and I
thought they could contribute there but
there was so many people at the project
already so I thought it would be more
interesting to go to a project and
nobody was absolutely yes that's right
and also the program is supposed to come
with new projects because there are
seven let's call them the domain experts
who came up with our with ideas for
projects because they are already in
contact or even part of ngos so they're
actually needed what is the need so and
adjunct different project which would
like to tell you about a little bit
which is called there to help you can
also find that already online its Web
284 that one and the target of that
project is to bring together NGOs and
their requirements and volunteers and
because volunteers are searching they
can offer this kid can offer the skills
can offer the tanks and it happened that
for example ngos posted something on
Facebook and Twitter and we need twenty
people for example just helping with
simple tasks 40 people showed up and
they couldn't make any use of them
because they couldn't organize them sent
twenty of them home the other 20 help
fight on the first created bed immediate
reactions but on the next day they
needed let's see another 21
so the first trendy couldn't help again
because they had to engage with a job
and the other 20 very frustrated from
day before the said maybe if I come back
again that will be sent for the second
time and that's not so we would like to
to have this in a more organized way and
also cross NGO exactly that's that's in
line 17 times and that's what we started
working on soul absolutely of course it
is already we haven't decided on the
election license up to now but in
Ceridian get up so you could look in the
refugee area of kidnap and find the
project there and it will soon be not
only available in source code form but
also in production so that they can use
it and that's what they currently
working on he has been working for two
days there and it was sort of a
contested I'm quite proud that he made
the first price there because yes
contest so the seven so the seven
projects were competing engine and we
the winning team in the great fun
because we really started its 0 just
started with the idea of fun and that's
also interesting on Luxembourg I his
guard Reggie and the interesting part
was he could talk to all the Austrian
engine ngos quite well because he speaks
fluently German but not only that he is
not an Austrian person so he isn't
engaged in a single NGO which could make
the other NGOs channels or something
like that so he was sort of a neutral
position and cooked bring several NGOs
21 Taemin talk to each other and that's
where happy he picked up that idea
talking about the public next match
making think tank and then he presented
to us
two people were doing project management
to people doing the background for the
application was one of these 22 people
were doing front and two more people
were doing an android client so this can
also be used as an Android application
and that was the may be the most funnest
the last one of the organizers was a bit
bored because everything was working
fine they did so great preparation
nothing talk about anything and
everything was running Essex maybe
better even than expected and so he was
a bit bored and the Chinese team because
that was a developer and he thought the
development and I so we could chill
screen shots at the end and impressed
then the jury in this Sept it could be
really something he was full and
something something easy to use for the
people and what was even more NY's is
that the project did not stop with the
final day but now more than a week has
passed and all of the people who
originally we're engaged in the project
we have I think more than 30 further
revisions of the software already have
next meetup next week and we have other
things planned as well so I hope to be
able to report on the project in future
success not only them or something like
that but actually the software used by
GEOS and volunteers absolutely it was
great fun to see that it's possible
within two hours to get something
working to get an organized
many organizations working people
collaborating even if they were from
different countries on guys coming in
from croatia we have an American guy we
have one from looks and book said before
his marlys project honor the request of
different items we have German dying we
have several people inside the team so
it's great fun to work in that group so
let me know that you had no yes we have
to disappoint
absolutely not that has nothing to do
with corporate world organization is
also useful in the project so people
decided to run the project management
and Davis sort of shielding hours from
the lots of requests coming from the
people with their ideas so because in
two days you can only achieve so many
absolutely absolutely our task is to get
an MVP as it's called running that means
a minimum viable provinces something
small that can actually be tested and
can be proven that diffuse and weekends
till later on in proved that wrong to
get more features to change that
absolutely and project management can
still be useful like is even necessary
and the people are still
in the project and help us different
the project which are maybe not so
technical and other developers are so
yes we are still
language was English of course it's
great I'm going to get a social needs of
course not only in every city but also
with different topics saw this was not
the first decathlon that has been
organized by that team for example they
did a full tank of fun because there's
so much food waste going on and they had
organized earlier you didn't try and
they plan to do other ones as well so
what is absolutely needed to sound like
you know people that superpower
good question I was thinking for this
could be I'm not so sure
meeting is a good idea what say so
especially when the people don't know
each other before and it's easier
because you can talk to each other quite
quickly I would say it depends maybe
even wanna social skills and the
technical skills because it there is no
immediate need to become something
technically out of the original sense
doesn't mean a program solution to a
problem
so there could be completely ways of
solutions coming out of something like
that and so different maybe around try
to get as many enthusiastic people about
the topic as possible then see what
skills they actually have and then out
of that decide what you can find a
problem that you can lose with use with
the skills and groups in smaller groups
because I think it was more than 40
people who were involved and building a
team of 40 people within such a short
time is probably not feasible so it's
easier to have smaller projects smaller
teams might even not sure if you make it
out with our nine people but finally
that worked out it's a surprise that it
worked out well because we were not so
sure of that group isn't to be yes the
first day in evening I'm not sure if
this went to where I would say it was a
lot of good luck this team found a job
but also when I saw the results on the
final day of presentations before so
that the jury could decide team and the
song I think five presentations went
from fourth member was really impressed
so there are lots of stuff so that there
was lots of good stuff at least lots of
interesting promising stuff coming out
just to give you maybe one more example
one project was refugees and then maybe
they don't really know each other but
they have so the idea is to messaging
application most of them have lots of
them have told the Independent by Fri so
it's something that is capable of using
wifi but then to have a messaging
application that is just reach chained
to a certain areas I'm interested to
talking to people which are ten
kilometers around me because that's more
or less within walking distance so we
could collaborate with each other she
expected patient's opportunities to help
people to communicate with you search a
reason
reaching put it to a situation that's
currently right now it could be useful
to restricted area even more let's just
take 500 metres area around me and it's
exactly are forming around the train
stations poor people are grouping around
the house as host them for the the time
and so they maybe it's also possible to
find a job or find people who have seen
interests or same capabilities because
they're always tasks to manage and it's
always good to do because then you can
continue living and not sitting around
depressed
where there any that were missing
whether some I think so that's the first
time I'm thinking and not in nineteen I
was not missing anybody and when we've
sometimes we had to look up the stuff of
course but the Internet is it will brush
or so and as stealing future times when
we need some experts on certain topics
trying to find him a big city with lots
of people lots of experts just have to
find them when you need them about you
would know we actually won some free
beer that was the best idea there was
always a price which is quite
interesting because because it's
breakfast at the hotel and the total is
very very special one because it's
around but former refugees only so I
don't know about half but we can look it
up and put it in China it's in the 2nd
district I know that refugees who are
running their total and I also knew that
from a four story where the Netherlands
who were living
guests at the pool chillin the very
happy very happy to be there they said
it was absolutely absolutely
professionally there and they could just
recommended to go there
not only because of the idea because of
the quality how the service provided so
that's a nice as the price is a
connection to refugees is all about some
cool so no no no
yeah maybe that's the kind of people who
show up at something like this because
you know we will be working hard for two
days and you know expectations out that
you'll have to start at least a little
bit more maybe it was still there were
lots lots more developers ratio the
usual so nice to see what it is that way
but it was fine and there was a new ad
hoc projects starting as well there's a
you know for example one guy who goes
he's developing web application
framework on top of another framework
and they need that they might pick a
shin so usually you're at the boring
stuff like 30022 application and he
decided that snapped the way to go he
wants to do something useful as well so
he picked up some ideas from
another project couldn't get ideas all
of her ideas for field so they started
the project on their own hearing that
this project is making progress so
there's also an Australian guy now
involved some funds so absolutely
doesn't matter in participating in such
a project report on the progress of the
project the city social space maybe yes
maybe that could be used even more so as
an example as a template in both ways in
the technical way because it's an
attempt as well so you can just go from
there but also content wise look what is
needed and maybe even because the people
who organized a very approachable so you
could talk to them and ask them sharing
side
just to change as well go to mention
this podcast is quoted think 22015 yeah
ok yes game it's a programming language
scratch its but it's really a story I
don't know which sorry but I know it it
has a story you are employee at the
enterprise and tomorrow corporation the
developer named tomorrow corporation to
you can know program and is nice I like
and yeah it's not yet and you that the
game released last week and so much I
can't pay for it so I have to get some
errands for it but now I have yeah if
you go to the homepage of tomorrow
corporation you can buy it on its home
page and it's a little plaque in from
its yeah one of one of you and the game
miss the graphical style and you have to
program to do want human you are the
employee has to do to do so
supervisor yeah yeah and you have to
program some steps simple steps
input band and yeah and okay and in and
out and some star like CPU registers and
on the band you have symbols like us and
let us and you can program took
something from them and take them I
would put a copy to the register in the
middle
yeah yeah and at the first only input
and output nature you have at something
and yeah you have something in your head
and at something similar in your head
and later you can put it on you have to
of course jam jam if not see if not
sorry if sorry 0 and champ if negative
yeah and then you can program touring
machine on it named its incremental and
so you can program for touring machine
it's something so you can see in this
list and it's possible to drag-and-drop
comments that's really important because
if your program complex program you have
to make comments left leg in assembler
not objective
because this language at the first you
have only yeah and what do you have to
do is the first complex and some
optimization steps
yes they have of steps in your list and
have steps to do each step and account
steps and if its smallest possible way
you buy it today and I will report and
forecast
described so you can read
machine works as CPU ya tomorrow
corporation I think it's a good idea I
get into this one is a member of the
name of that game so I have to look it
up and running JavaScript it's an online
games you don't have to restore its one
a lot and still didn't come to proper
solutions their task is that you have to
program an elevator but do you get the
specific language what you can do with
inanimate and depending on conditions
you can program in the beginning there
and then it's quite easy just go down
and make it look every request
domestically but then it gets harder and
harder and liberals read it wasn't a
chance doing it by writing it down so
people iraq was absolutely and then
change the program and trying to fulfill
the task for example getting fifty
people to talk to the people have the
certain targets and that's just so talk
to my mind I saw it last week there is
quite an intense community forming
around Commodore 64 again it's quite
funny game and the funny thing is how
many games during the history it's been
never more than 2014 so it's still
increasing current by the machine you
can sometimes get the chance to buy new
ones
the biggest problem is that the process
so if they can get some chips like the
process system in processes the GPU
graphics chip on that done an
extraordinary then you can buy new main
boards and you can buy new cases that
can be done and there was quite a bit
community forming around with with new
episodes and stuff and was an
interesting approach is how to
circumvent the issue that you cannot get
the new machine
is gonna do you see me later so machines
are currently so fast that on a problem
smartphone you can just download an
emulator and games it's it's it's yeah
and keep in mind there is it was a mess
to us but now you program that on your
PC with a fool I D E which gives you
called completion and stuff and you have
the internet open a second window and
look up too many pages there and then
you came to play and he thinks it's
moralist two groups would you describe
the old guys because it's not seem to
have the feeling that it's gonna be easy
to do but there is always a group of
young people communities communities
online exchange knowledge put up to 20
yrs brokaw's as it's done now with any
community
but yes I know you have in mind that
there are lots of restrictions there and
lots of these restrictions can be
circumvented by being clever so it's you
have to prove yourself that you can get
around these restrictions if you
remember that demos from there is seen
right now again and giving the number of
them which are published growing and
also the material that spark plug on the
internet it's getting more and more so
for example i've seen they must now with
336 with shaders and even I don't know
how you would call that you see a stick
figure it's really stick figure animated
so they do break things and then saying
yes yes
process and
well and I think you mentioned the word
restrictions and so that's a huge
because when you're developing for all
and deciding between there's a lot that
it's not just the older people that had
Commodore 64 yrs but if we develop
something new and cool and retro it's
like an old car now we're told Radio or
an old piece of furniture I think and
and the 64 was that most it it's the
best of all time it was it was in the
market for so long that it has this sort
of mythic
I get excited selfishly because I'm
writing a novel that takes place in the
near future but about a young girl whose
mother gives her Commodore 64 because
she doesn't know that it how older
computer it is just finds it is in a
thrift shop but that girl is able to do
so much more with her comment or and
then her peers can do with their closed
computers so I think there's a pill to
something that you can that's easy to
hack code what about these machines
which cannot be done with the current
machines so there is a busy it's not
it's ok so you had
and is appealing is quite easy to learn
to ya machine with 16 purchasers risk
the process of different machines for
example in the first nine ten intend or
game engine so you can run then you
cannot support devices which are
simulated interesting but not so much
its it will be tomorrow for us we have
2010 end tomorrow
machine will arrive but he won't find
Hobart's so that's a big impact and 20th
Century Fox produced
advertise or have a box so they have
pepsi has owned for this stage because
in Back to the Future two but woods and
ease of use now and some other things
reshaped in transportation there is an
action connection to that because today
they brought out traffic regulation over
boards and if you have time there are
some triple feature in some cinema us
here in Germany and Austria it I think
in America too and I think every
tomorrow
streets empty and
yeah
yeah just want to experience what they
need and keeps my sticky so it's not
dangerous for kids playing with it
because its law
and low and you don't need to sort of
like a very simple keyboard so clip in
different areas to control scratch or
control of video game that one of my
favorite is using pepper slices of
pepperoni control of PowerPoint so left
and right slices of pizza that's a very
playful thing they say it's an invention
kit for everyone and it turns everyday
objects into ways to control your
computer so using water or being able to
create your own game controllers they
have to jump up and down like I'm a
trampoline to jump in Mario Land or some
kind of platform it is it invites
creativity I think in a really cool
we're doing into the real world instead
of just on the computer
experience with the making make it to
last podcast but I talked about and I
talked about game program with Ed and we
used to make him a keys as inputs to we
had booked you have to turn the pages to
come to make eye contact and trying and
something else I don't remember and this
something like it was a music games and
you have to pay its ok I wanna hear
someone and you can control this ads and
yes we try it again and we thought about
to use padding but yeah it works really
easy
one of the first things I always kids
the creators of me hehe it was G so we
we mention Eric Rosenbaum in another
podcast because he created way to do 3d
and scratch so OJ and Eric were both
part of the lifelong kindergarten group
at MIT they've both got their PHD's last
year but they were still students and
they raise the money to manufacture by
doing a Kickstarter campaign so is
crowd-sourced which is great and they
even donated several making me he's for
me to bring to Africa for Africa code
week so directly indirectly yeah so I
was able to leave four of them in Africa
at two different schools and so I have a
bunch of students working on projects
that there cannot report back as a way
to have continuity after a good week so
it's pretty cool yeah there's there's a
fantastic will link to a TED talk by Jay
silver about why he wanted to create
Miki Miki partially inspired by a trip
to a third world country I think in
South America where he was really
impressive the way that kids make all
sorts of things just grass and leaves
and things that they found in the jungle
and wondered if there was a way to bring
that to First World kids and and making
me he was his response to that that's
really cool yeah I remember weeks in
there was a presentation from the Fox
guy he demonstrated tournament in the
browser that's the topic but he has used
to make make you and us
yeah but it's not impossible to to take
the banana and shoot with banners not
yet that's what I like about it is that
it uses real-world objects that that
people can find like at the scratch
conference last summer people were doing
musical instruments rubbish from a
Starbucks cafe cops and aluminum and all
that stuff and so I think it really gets
a new level of creativity such a device
for scratch is also making their own
custom controllers for maybe 10 top 10
most heartwarming moments his father who
has a son with cerebral palsy or some
other disease so his son cap move his
body very well and his father can create
custom keyboard based on the movement
that has so it's really enabling people
to do engineering that might not
otherwise be able to control of computer
and it doesn't require any drivers it's
just plug and play with PC Mac and Linux
in Sanaa McKee bought a used a mouse but
it's limited to things to 16
piece it's not possible to emulate our
key brought over hundreds keys and the
funny thing is on this making making it
there so I do we know CPU is so you can
use it as yet on the BART yeah it's not
really new but it's totally comfortable
do we know that the same ship so you can
program your own programs because it
lets you control the mouse position and
it even has acceleration with you its
mouth gradually accelerates just like a
mouse water truck but it's really very
helpful they also they have a there's
another product they gave me one to
bring to Africa called Dr vo which they
did together and it lets you have this
little circuit with a speaker on a brush
or pencil and then water or paint or
pencil and becomes medium for doing that
you can have basic sound so you can you
can sort of pain
yeah which is something that has been
exploring with touch-based interfaces
with iPad apps so we don't know if you
saw his demo but yeah
yeah so singing fingers is the app that
we did another podcast and he also has a
thing called melody morphs that really
explores the way that you can create
your music so a way for children to
Greek music with their voices and their
fingers and and this concept of what it
called when you cross the different
senses together like touch and feel and
touch and yeah more like there's a word
for you your senses get sort of cross
when you taste colors this idea of
crossing
inspired paint and talk by Joseph fill
out this card when I met him in Bern and
three years ago where he was talking
about the use of language and
programming we sometimes miss you so
comparing to language literature
progress very inspiring and now three
years later met him again science book
and was expecting something about
literature again but now he switched
complete his area where he's working
more or less I would say an artist and
not so much anymore he's doing actual
performances with sunny pious which are
used in school for teaching about
programming teaching about music and all
that stuff together and he uses it for
action performances which contain of
course of sounds so he also gave a live
performance at the audience insights
book it was quite because there was six
six hundred attendees
lights were dimmed down credible
small sonic pie filling up the whole
whole conference hall and not only did
he provide us with incredible sound but
also with animations which can quite
easily be included into Sonic pie
programs and there is mean by then I was
looking into Sonic biofuels from me look
not very approachable and not very
appealing and that has so much progress
so called before I just looking on the
screen project and as the background of
the screen he used animations and give
this presentation that was really
awesome you could hear if somebody would
have dropped his besides the sounds he
was producing and in the beginning
seem to be quite easy because he started
from scratch but in the end it was
something may be heard or seen from a
full performance for profit and in real
time with programming just created on
the fly
know nothing proves group did he just
knew you could see his face when he was
pleased with something and for every now
and then that Sonic prize catches areas
however now intended to me stipend it
especially yeah it it doesn't crash but
it gives you an error message and tries
to help you a little bit how you can
figure out and afterwards I talked a
little bit because I was asked him as
well if you did preparations in the set
of course he knows his stuff more or
less but still experimenting with with
the numbers and the filters and the
instruments and on and on certain
point in time he just mistyped and
something came out that he wasn't
expecting so he was a little bit shocked
because he was expecting something
completely different but shocked about
he started to like it so we thought why
not get in until noon and then changed
his further performance of that was
really nice to see that it actually
sonic price and entry he he asked him
how much training does here and he told
us he does this now for more than two
years and almost every day's just trying
to get better and tease locks you you
can lock sonic pay foot and his locks
captured and he publishes I'm on the
internet so we are able to download them
and learn from him how is that was
really the most artistic stuff I've ever
seen at the program in conference but
I'm not sure I'm not sure it's almost
shocking chair so he becomes quite small
onto that stage and suddenly he rocks it
by program
traveling in meeting people from not
just roam or even Italy but all over the
world over there do you think because
Germany cannot participate and next you
should come to Austin
suppose this is an international
trudge through energy or transportation
3d fabrication
yeah when I think about the Maker Faire
bring to us so you have seen their
musical instruments we saw an incredible
device that played an acoustic guitar so
they built this machine that would play
any music it immediately guitar into
like a music box music into it and then
it would block with some devices also
expected
created but it was projects each other
and then there were a few huge tents
dedicated just for children to tinker
with things I participated in some
scratch workshops they were robotics and
even more like artsy arts and crafts
take things so tons of families going
through like children are also allowed
to come in and take three items with you
from making over there she died
would have taken there was a bicycle
frame was made out of bamboo and then
there was a skateboard grass or hay or
something really interesting and then I
really wanted this Airstream trailer
that had been converted into a
children's coding laboratory like a
portable laboratory that I took more
pictures of that one Airstream trailer
so call it the whole side opened out
kids in to try out this really cool girl
with her and trigger some new projects
may be for you
together they had different workshops
for children that could just show up and
and trav robotics and a little bit of
programming in a little bit of design so
that's that's something that if I went
back I'd love to do more preparation for
having more spaces where kids could
explore things together and forced me to
great friend who was doing minecraft
modding stuff using running on raspberry
PI's in there was a ton of people have
developed a Raspberry Pi accessories
different touch screens for Raspberry Pi
displays and input devices in boxes and
so really seems like people are
embracing the open architecture of
things like raspberry pie and Arduino
some things so sometimes people come out
and I managed to get you for ten people
but it it seems like that that could
have been tied into the beaker sends a
little bit more they be there are some
food like some interesting ways to
prepare food or water on families China
so I call to talk to me
so there was no no complaining it seems
nobody complete and now to translate
earliest after some point up and out
so you just as you say so and yeah it
was part of it was exciting is just see
that you don't have to be an American
car company or in america to do really
innovative things with electronics
computers so it I think it was so great
to be outside of the USA and and to be
surrounded by these really innovative
people from all over Europe and it just
reminded me that americans don't own
innovation there's innovation all over
the place and I think also being in
Italy there was a sense of
this historical connection engineering
innovations through the centuries so
every time I saw something with fabric
or something with an engine or something
with engineering it made me think of the
great Italian pioneers like DaVinci
being the poster child for innovation
and even some of the ways that drones
were designed they look like beautiful
DaVinci drawings I think style was a
much bigger part than what we might see
another Maker Faires because of the
Italian emphasis and historical ties
design so that was really cool
all the hard surfaces of the train but
we were very fortunate with our sleeper
cars I'm grateful that we didn't sleeper
car they get a shot she responded to you
for you